A Finding Aid to the Frances Wolfson Art Gallery Records, 1973-1994, in the Archives of American Art AAA.franwola
Archives of American Art
Frances Wolfson Art Gallery records
1973-1994
AAA.franwola
Archives of American Art
5 Linear feet
The records of the Frances Wolfson Art Gallery measure 5 linear feet and date from 1973 to 1994 with 4.5 linear feet documenting exhibitions held at the Gallery. General administration of the Gallery is also chronicled through correspondence, business records and printed material.
Frances Wolfson Art Gallery
Biographical/Historical note
The Frances Wolfson Art Gallery was established in 1976 on the Mitchell Wolfson New World Center Campus of the Miami-Dade Community College. It focused on the art of the local Latino community in addition to serving the needs of the College's arts and humanities students. Exhibitions and lectures reflected four major areas of emphasis: the Hispanic community, the Black community, the relationship of art, architecture and culture to the quality of contemporary urban civilization, and the best of new artists presented in solo or cohesive group exhibitions.
Director from 1978 to 1981, Roberta Griffin was followed in that position by Sheldon Lurie in September 1981 until his death in October 1990.
In the spring of 1987, the Frances Wolfson Art Gallery implemented an active exhibition program at the InterAmerican Center in the form of the InterAmerican Art Gallery. Located in the Little Havana section of Miami, the major thrust of this gallery is Hispanic art, reflecting the interests and needs of the surrounding community.
Scope and Contents note
The records of the Frances Wolfson Art Gallery comprise 5 linear feet of material dating from 1973 to 1994. The collection contains correspondence, routine business records, exhibition files, notes, printed material, and photographs of artists, installations, and works of art, and is arranged into seven series according to material type. The bulk of the material relates to exhibitions held at the Gallery from 1977 to 1992 in exhibition files measuring 4.5 linear feet. The general administration of the Gallery is also partially documented through business records and correspondence files.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as six series according to material type. Records are arranged chronologically unless otherwise noted.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1976-1994 (Box 1; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 2: Business Records, 1981-1993 (Box 1; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 3: Notes, 1973-1987 (Box 1; 2 folders)
Series 4: Exhibition Files, 1977-1992, undated (Boxes 1-5; 4.5 linear feet)
Series 5: Printed Material, 1974-1994 (Box 5; 5 folders)
Series 6: Color Transparencies of Artwork, 1983-1990 (Box 5; 10 items)
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
This collection was donated to the Archives of American Art by the Miami-Dade Community College in 1997
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of unmicrofilmed material in the holdings of the Archives of American Art requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C., facility.
Azaceta, Luis Cruz, 1942-; Bencomo, Mario, 1953-; Chisolm, Michael; Day, Larry, 1921-; Dionisio, Humberto, 1950-1987; Katzen, Lila; Larraz, Julio; McGarrell, James, 1930-; Piper, Jane, 1916-; Art galleries, University and college--Florida--Miami; Art, Modern--20th century--Florida--Miami--Exhibitions; Artists--Florida--Miami; Cuban American artists--Florida--Miami; Hispanic American art--Florida--Miami; Hispanic American artists--Florida--Miami
- Correspondence, 1976-1994; Series 1; 0.2 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  General Gallery Correspondence primarily consists of letters regarding proposed exhibitions which were never executed. These contain between one and three letters from various artists and others including Mario Bencomo, Deborah Brown, Rosemarie Chiarlone, Luis Cruz-Azaceta (one illustrated letter), Susan Emery Eisenberg (one illustrated holiday card), Dale Eldred, Scott Hartley, Marcia Isaacson, Lila Katzen, Alice Lewis, Dan Rice, Michael J. Sastre, Tom Seghi, Alice Terry, and Regina Vater.
  The correspondence files for the Cultural Executives Council, Inc., InterAmerican Art Gallery, and National Foundation for Advancement in the Arts consists of letters exchanged with each institution.
  Arrangement note
  General Gallery Correspondence records are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. The Cultural Executives Councils, Inc., InterAmerican Art Gallery, and National Foundation for Advancement in the Arts are filed in their own folders.
  - General Gallery Correspondence, 1976-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1-18)
  - Cultural Executives Council, Inc., 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 19-23)
  - InterAmerican Art Gallery, Miami-Dade Community College, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - National Foundation for Advancement in the Arts, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 25-27)
- Business Records, 1981-1993; Series 2; 0.2 Linear feet Box 1
  This series consists of annual reports, personnel records, travel records, a telephone log, Miami-Dade Community College Foundation accounts, invoices from Worldwide Books, and miscellaneous financial records.
  Records are arranged by subject.
  - Annual Reports, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 28-36)
  - Personnel Records, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Travel Records, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 38-40)
  - Telephone Log, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Miami-Dade Community College Foundation Accounts, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Invoices from Worldwide Books, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Records, 1982-1993 (Box 1, Folder 44-46)
- Notes, 1973-1987; Series 3; 2 Folders Box 1
  These two folders include various artists' resumés, including those of Michael R. Chisolm, Houston Conwill, Larry Day, Ronna S. Harris, Jane Piper, Raquel Rabinovich, Michael Rossman, Eduardo Serrano Rueda, Doris Staffel, Burton E. Van Deusen, and Judith Wilson.
  - Miscellaneous Resumés, 1973-1987 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Exhibition Files, 1977-1992, undated; Series 4; 4.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-5
  The exhibition files form the bulk of the collection and document 116 exhibitions at the Frances Wolfson Art Gallery. The files typically contain any or all of the following: resumés, gallery correspondence, letters from artists, loan agreements, price lists, financial records, notes, typescripts, exhibition catalogs and other printed material, photographs of artists, and photographs, transparencies, contact sheets and negatives of artwork and installations. Dates of exhibitions appear in parentheses and are immediately followed by span dates of material in each folder.
  Records are arranged chronologically by exhibition with undated exhibitions at the beginning of the series. Italics indicate the title of an exhibition when known.
  - Clare Jeanine Satin Exhibition, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - The Art of Aramis O'Reilly, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Recent Paintings, Louis Ulman, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Video Festival (Oct 3-23, 1977) (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Vito Acconci, John Baldessari, Peter Campus, Simone Forti, Hermine Freed, Joan Jonas, Richard Serra, Keith Sonnier, and William Wegman
  - The Secret Paris of the Thirties (Nov 16-Dec 16, 1977) (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Brassai
  - Artists' Sketchbooks and Preparatory Drawings (Jan 5-25, 1978), 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Ralston Crawford and Unidentified Artists
  - Richard Hunt Exhibition (Feb 13-Mar 3, 1978) (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Video Photograph Exhibition (Sept 11-28, 1978) (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Eleanor Antin, Wendy Clark, Hermine Freed, Amy Greenfield, Joan Jonas, and Hannah Wilke
  - Paintings (Oct 12-Nov 8, 1978), 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Lynne Golob Gelfman
  - Nevelson: The Prints (1979), 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Louise Nevelson
  - Congo Images (Jan 29, 1979) (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Mildred Clouse
  - Faculty Exhibition 1979 (Mar 5-30, 1979) (Box 1, Folder 60)
    Rick Freshee, David Gossoff, Marilyn Gottlieb-Roberts, Roberta Griffin, Bruce Posner, and Jean Ward
  - Anne Minich: Recent Works (Nov 5-27, 1979) (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Faculty Exhibition 1980 (Mar 5-30, 1980) (Box 1, Folder 62)
    David Gossoff, Marilyn Gottlieb-Roberts, Roberta Griffin, Carol Levy, and Jean Ward
  - New Columbians/Salon 80 (Jul 10-Aug 26, 1980), 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    Alvaro Alegria, Edgar Alvarez, Luis Aragon, Oscar Arcila, Ever Astudillo, Orlando Atencio, Jose Carlos Caicedo, Ivan Alejandro Castillo, Carlos Correa, Norey Agudelo de Mejia, Otilia de Wolter, Carlos Adolfo Dominguez, Patricia Escobar, Juan Nicolas Estela, Rosastella Fernandez, Pablo Galvez, Oscar Garcia, Miguel Birmaher Ghitis, Gustavo Hernandez, Bernardino Labrada, Edison Lara, Salomon Londono, Alberto Lopez, Alvaro Lozano, Mario Alonso Lozano, Jose Mina, Roberto Molano, Yesid Montana, Jorge Montealegre, Evaristo Okendo Montes, Luis Mario Murillo, Cesar Narino, Marcolfo Obregon, Hector Fabio Oviedo, Luis Carlos Palacios, Inez Valencia Pardo, Jaime Piedrahita, Carlos Posso, Cesar Santafe, Marino Tenorio, Alvaro Valbuena, Mario Roldan Villa, and Jaime Wiesner (with photographs of the five winners: Jorge Montealeagre, Luis Carlos Palacios, Jose Mina, Alvaro Valbuena, and Roberto Molano)
  - Juan Gonzalez Exhibition (Oct 9-Nov 13, 1980), 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Elaine Kurtz: Color Illusion (Jan 12-Feb 6, 1981), 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Concepts of Self in African Art (Feb 16-Mar 11, 1981), 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Community College Faculty/Student Exhibition (April 13-May 15, 1981) (Box 1, Folder 67)
    Barbara Cabana, Jorge de Rojas, Juan Carlos Garcia, David Gossoff, Marilyn Gottlieb-Roberts, Roberta Griffin, Katarina Isaakson, Sheldon M. Lurie, Roberto Regalado, Milton Sharp, and Matthew Wilson
  - Centro Colombo Americano Exhibition (May 1-Aug 15, 1981) (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Marilyn Gottlieb-Roberts, Roberta Griffin, Sheldon M. Lurie, Mary Taylor, and Jean Ward (professors); Pablo Cano, Jorge de Rojas, Katrina Isaakson, and Matthew Wilson (students)
  - Hard Times: Photographs from the Farm Security Administration (May 11-Jun 24, 1981), 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    John Collier, Jack Delano, Walker Evans, Tina Freeman Theo Jung, Dorothea Lange, Russell Lee, Carl Mydans, Arthur Rothstein, Ben Shahn, John Vachon, and Marion Post Wolcott
  - Film Forms: Independent Films and Film-Makers from Chicago, Buffalo and Pittsburgh (Jun 2-5, 1981) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Gary Adkins, Peggy Ahwesh, Stan Brakhage, Renate Breth, James Broughton, Tony Buba, Tony Conrad, Hollis Frampton, Nora Jacobson, George Landow, Barbara Lattanzi, John Luther, Una McClure, Rich Moore, Steve Osborn, Tom Palazzolo, Marcelle Pecot, Rick Pieto, Bruce Posner, Mark Rance, Alan Ross, Keith Sanborn, Paul Sharits, Jan Sutcliffe, Jim Vale, Natulka Voslakov, and Sarah Woodward
  - Latin American Art: A Woman's View (Oct 5-Nov 13, 1981) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Maria Brito-Avellana, Ana Mendieta, and Elena Presser
  - City Sequence: Photographs by Gary Monroe and from the Collection of the Historical Association of Southern Florida (Nov 18-Dec 16, 1981), 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Photographer At Large (Jan 11-Feb 26, 1982) (Box 2, Folder 5-7)
    Gordon Parks
  - In Celebration of Age: Twentieth Century Artists in Their 70's & 80's (Mar 8-Apr 16, 1982), 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Jean Arp, Ilya Bolotowsky, Harry Callahan, Morris Hirshfield, Lee Krasner, Leon Kroll, Agnes Martin, Joan Miro, Henry Moore, Mary Robinson Moses, Louise Nevelson, Betty Parsons, Pablo Picasso, Aaron Siskind, Esphyr Slobodkina, Raphael Soyer, George Sugarman, Jack Tworkov, and Claire Zeisler
  - New Directions: Clay & Fiber (Sept 6-Oct 4, 1982) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Jim Adamson, Bennett Bean, Frank Boyden, Victor Citrin, Tom Coleman, Richard Deutsch, Margaret Ford, Margie Hughto, Jenny Lind, Rina Peleg, Sally Prange, and Tom Turner (clay); Dina Barzel, Cornelia Breitenbach, Patricia Campbell, Kathy Constantinides, Nancy Crow, Judith Fawkes, Layne Goldsmith, Nancy Halpern, Janice Lessman-Moss, John McQueen, Nance O'Banion, Arturo Sandoval, Sherri Smith, Shigeko Spear, and Janice Wagstaff (fiber)
  - Origins of Modern Cuban Painting (Oct 11-Nov 11, 1982) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Carlos Enriquez, Victor Manuel Garcia, Amelia Pelaez del Casal, Fidelio Ponce de Leon, and Leopoldo Romanach
  - Florida Artists See Themselves (Nov 17-Dec 21, 1982), 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 11-15)
    Maria Brito-Avellana, Jill Cannady, Michael Carlebach, James Couper, Mario Egozi, Marilyn Gottlieb-Roberts, Marvelle Adler Kaplan, Jeffrey Kronsnoble, Edith Timberlake Landowne, Maria Lino, Sheldon M. Lurie, Eugene Massin, Abigail Perlmutter, Elena Presser, Beryl Solla, Louis Ulman, Jean Ward, William Ward, Hiram Williams, and Gerald G. Winter
  - Thunder Over Miami: Ritual Objects of Nigerian and Afro-Cuban Religion (Jan 30-Feb 23, 1983) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - The Art of Robert Courtright (Mar 3-Apr 14, 1983) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Marilyn Gottlieb-Roberts: Light Ambulant (May 20-Jun 23, 1983), 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - American Studies, Michael Carlebach (Aug 31-Sept 30, 1983) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The Art of Santiago Cardenas (Oct 6-Nov 1, 1983), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - Weston and Laughlin in Louisiana (Dec 2, 1983-Jan 13, 1984), 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Clarence John Laughlin and Edward Weston
  - Ellery Kurtz: Fragments (Mar 23-Apr 20, 1984) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - New Figure Drawing: Twelve Latin American Artists (Oct 11-Nov 9, 1984), 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 25-29)
    Rodolfo Abularach, Alfredo Castaneda, Fernando Colon, Luis Cruz-Azaceta, Delia Cugat, Juan Downey, Luis Frangella, Paulo Gomes Garcez, Maria Lino, Benjamin Lira, Ramiro Llona, and Jorge Tacla
  - Works by Jorge Montealegre (Oct 12-Nov 9, 1984), 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Jorge Montealegre (and Cesar Santafe)
  - Works by Tom McCarthy (Nov 1984) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Perceptions: Black & White (1985), 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Rosemarie Castoro, J. Pinto, Livio Saganic, and Krzysztof Wodicko
  - Alumni Invitational II (Jun 6-Jul 25, 1985), 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Adam Straus and Phyllis Lindsey Straus
  - Florida Figures (Sept 6-30, 1985), 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 34-38)
    Carlos Alfonzo, Shareyar Ataie, Marcia Athens, Robert Beach, Theresa Beck, Cheryl Bogdanowitsch, Maria Brito-Avellana, Thomas Burke, Ramon Carulla, Walt Chaney, Jim Cogswell, James Couper, Jerry Cutler, Richard Frank, Marcia Isaacson, Grady Kimsey, Elizabeth Kowalchuk, David Kremgold, Jeffrey Kronsnoble, Adriano Lambe, Jean-Louis Lebrun, Maria Lino, Sheldon M. Lurie, Thomas Minor, Arturo Rodriguez, Kenny Schneider, Jeanne Schubert, Henry Sinn, Beryl Solla, Jean Ward, Jeff Whipple, and Laura Wortzel
  - Benjamin Lira: Paintings 1981-1985 (Oct 10-Nov 8, 1985), 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - World Landscape: Photographs by William Farnsworth (Nov 14-Dec 18, 1985), 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Perceptions: Black & White (Jan 9-Feb 7, 1986), 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Bobby G (Robert J. Goldman), Grace Graupe-Pillard, and Arturo Rodriguez
  - In Site: Ten South Florida Sculptors (Feb 7-Apr 30, 1986), 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Mary Lee Ataie, Carol Brown, Robert Chambers, Christine Federighi, Robert Huff, Peter Kuentzel, Jean Claude Rigaud, Jim Rosburg, Robert Thiele, and Jean Ward
  - The Art of Cynthia Hawkins (Feb 13-Mar 14, 1986), 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - New Images: Carol Levy and Maria Lino (Mar 20-Apr 17, 1986) (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Sandy Winters Exhibition (Nov 13-Dec 17, 1986), 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - The Art of Louis Delsarte (Feb 12-Mar 13, 1987), 1979-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Violence and Television: Paintings by Jerry Cutler (Mar 19-Apr 17, 1987), 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - In Print Miami (Aug 27-Sept 25, 1987) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Marie Lee Ataie, Shahreyar Ataie, Robert Huff, Anriano Lambe, Carol S. Levy, Arturo Rodriguez, Deborah Schneider, Kenny Schneider, Robert Ransom Thiele, and Gene Sinclair Tinnie
  - Watercolor Now! (Sept 3-Oct 1, 1987), 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Linda Chapman, Richard J. Frank, Juan Pastorelli, and Charles Seliger
  - Cubiles: Recent Paintings (Oct 1-Nov 24, 1987), 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Miguel Cubiles de la Rosa (includes two illustrated letters)
  - Arturo Rodriguez, 1977-1987 (Oct 8-Nov 5, 1987) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Known/Unknown I (Nov 12-Dec 15, 1987) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Marcia E. Athens, Thomas F. Minor, and James Scott Witherell
  - In Between: Born in Cuba/Raised in Miami (Dec 3, 1987-Jan 27, 1988), 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Roly Chang Barrero, Guillermo Gonzalez, Maria Lino, and Pablo Mirabal
  - The Art of Carlos Alfonzo (Jan 7-Feb 5, 1988) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Twentieth Century Cuban Art: Selections from the Collection of Ramon Cernuda and Nercys Ganem (Feb 5-Mar 30, 1988) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Eduardo Abela, Cundo Bermudez, Mario Carreno, Roberto Diago, Antonia Eiriz, Carlos Enriquez, Roberto Estopinan, Agustin Fernandez, Victor Manuel Garcia, Angel Acosta Leon, Jose M. Mijares, Raul Milian, Servando Cabrara Moreno, Amelia Pelaez del Casal, Gina Pellon, Fidelio Ponce de Leon, Rene Portocarrero, Domingo Ravenet, Mariano Rodriguez, Arturo Rodriguez, and Aristides Fernandez Vasquez
  - Perspectives (Feb 11-Mar 11, 1988), 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Camille Billops and Kabuya Pamela Bowens
  - Paintings and Drawings (Mar 1988), 1983-1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    James A. Cogswell
  - Known/Unknown II (Apr 7-Jun 1, 1988) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Demi (Rodriguez) and Elvira Huergo
  - XII Annual Juried Student Exhibition (Apr 21-May 27, 1988) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Alumni Invitational (Jun 2-Jul 18, 1988) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Juan Carlos Garcia-Lavin and John Harms
  - Sculpture As History (Sept 1-30, 1988) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Shahreyar Ataie, Ward M. Shelley, and Phyllis Straus
  - A Woman's Eye: Black & White Photography (Sept 8-Oct 7, 1988) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Cecilia Arboleda, Carmen Junquera, Maria Lantigua, Becky Mayer, and Teresa Rodriguez-Smith
  - Finis Terrae/The Ends of the Earth (Oct 6-Nov 3, 1988), 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 18-20)
    Juan Downey, Ismael Frigerio, and Jorge Tacla
  - The Chicano Experience (Oct 13-Nov 30, 1988), 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    John Hernandez and Benito Huerta
  - Manipulations: Photographs by Roger Cutforth & Maria Martinez-Canas (Nov 10-Dec 15, 1988), 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Known/Unknown III (Dec 8, 1988-Jan 25, 1989), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Jose Bernardo Perez and Grace Hedrick-Welti
  - Alumni Exhibition '89 (1989) (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Julieta Pinedo Posada and McKenzie Smith
  - Artists' Proofs: Printmaking in South Florida (Jan 5-Feb 3, 1989), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Carlos Alfonzo, Shahreyar Ataie, Marcia Athens, Kabuya Pamela Bowens, Brian Curtis, Ron Fondaw, Scott Hartley, Shirley Henderson, Elvira Huergo, Carol Levy, Maria Lino, S. M. Lurie, Tom Minor, Arturo Rodriguez, and Debbie Schneider
  - Painting in 3-Dimensions Nadine DeLawrence-Maine (Feb 9-Mar 5, 1989), 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Latin American Art from Private Collections (Apr 6-May 31, 1989), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Juan Abreu, Carlos Alfonzo, Mario Bencomo, Maria Brito-Avellana, Alfredo Castaneda, Luis Cruz-Azaceta, Lilian Cuenca, Demi [Rodriguez], Emilio Falero, Elvira Huergo, Benito Huerta, Juan Lezcano, Benjamin Lira, Ana Mendieta, Tony Mendoza, Elena Presser, George Queral, Arturo Rodriguez, Paul Sierra, Cesar Trasobares, and Rafael Vadia
  - Known/Unknown IV (Aug 31-Sept 29, 1989) (Box 3, Folder 28)
    William Latham and Karen Rifas
  - Julio Larraz: Process (Oct 5-31, 1989) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - The Art of Arnaldo Roche Rabell (Oct 12-Nov 30, 1989) (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Art Against AIDS II (Nov 3, 1989) (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Elements of Landscape: Photographs by Aaron Siskind & Barry Fellman (Nov 9-Dec 12, 1989) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Known/Unknown V (Dec 7, 1989-Jan 31, 1990), 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Gary Feinberg and Maria Sonia Martin
  - Recent Paintings (Jan 11-Feb 9, 1990) (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Deborah Schneider
  - The Post-Miami Generation (Feb 8-Mar 30, 1990) (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Rene Aguilar, Luisa M. Basnuevo, Jose Bernardo, Juan Carlos Garcia-Lavin, Guillermo Gonzalez, Maria Martinez-Canas, Alberto Torre de Alba, and Tomas Touron
  - New Perspectives (Feb 15-Mar 16, 1990), 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    Colin Chase and Whitfield Lovell
  - Venezuela: The Next Generation (Feb 28-Mar 22, 1990), 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
    Susana Amundarain, Maria Eugenia Arria, Ricardo Benaim, Antonio Lazo, Ernesto Leon, Luis Lizardo, Felix Perdomo, Jorge Pizzani, and Carlos Sosa
  - Fractured Spaces: Recent Works by Francisco Alvarado-Juarez (Apr 5-May 31, 1990) (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - The Art of James McGarrell (May 10-Jul 5, 1990), 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 40-48)
  - Humberto Dionisio: A Retrospective (Jun 7 Jul 31, 1990) (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Two Decades of Hispanic Theater In Miami: A Retrospective of Photographs by Asela Torres, (Aug 13-31, 1990) (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Known/Unknown VI (Sept 6-Oct 17, 1990), 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    Tony Galardi and Sebastian Spreng (includes 5 photographs by Galardi)
  - Prints (Sept 7-Oct 5, 1990), 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 52-53)
    Leon Golub
  - Priests Series and Oracion: Valentine's Day/Day of the Dead Series (Oct 11-Dec 7, 1990), 1983-1991 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    Kathy Vargas
  - The Art of Luis Frangella (Oct 25, 1990-Jan 18, 1991), 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Recent Paintings and Works on Paper (Jan-Feb 1991), 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Robert Huff
  - The Rage of Children (Jan 11-Feb 1, 1991), 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5-15)
    Willie Birch, Sue Coe, Luis Cruz-Asaceta, Demi [Rodriguez], Mike Glier, Sharon Jacques, Maria Lino, Sheldon Lurie, Arturo Rodriguez, and Helen Stummer
  - At the Edge (Jan 31-Apr 19, 1991), 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Fanny Sanin
  - Art and Social Commentary (Apr 21-26, 1991) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Kim Irwin
  - Contemporaries in Our Midst (May 2-18, 1991) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Manuel Acevedo, Tom Paquette, and Sherri Tan, Fellows of National Foundation for Advancement in the Arts (NFAA), Career Advancement of Visual Artists Program (CAVA); see also May 7-28, 1992 (Box 5, Folders 35-37)
  - No Easy Walk: Voices of the Inner City (May 2-Jun 14, 1991), 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 19-21)
    Helen Stummer
  - Recent Works (May 9-Jun 7, 1991) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    David Krueger (includes transcript of an interview with Krueger conducted by Jean Martin of New York City)
  - Intermix Installations Festival 2 (Jul 31-Aug 3, 1991) (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Adalberto Delgado, Jorge Pizzani, and Ward Shelley
  - Costa Rica Exhibition (Aug 26-Sept 6, 1991) (Box 4, Folder 24-26)
    Raul Aguilar, Martalicia Almeida, Rodrigo Brenes, Dinorah Carballo, Fernando Carballo, Miguel Casafont, Paz Esquivel Cascante, Emilia Cersosimo, Liz Chacon, Lola Fernandez, Christina Fournier, Sandra Freck, Dora Gonzalez, Libia Isabel Gutierrez, Jose Pablo Hernandez, Maria Herrero, Ricardo Jimenez, Isabel Naranjo, Hector Olivares, Paulina Ortiz, Cecilia Pastor, Virginia Perez-Ratton, Teresa Porras, Mariano Prado, Margarita Quesada, Jorge Rojas, Alejandro Sequeira, Alonso Toruno, Ricardo Ulloa, Lorena Valdeperas, Sonia Vargas, and Guita Zonzinski
  - The South Florida Collective 1 (Sept 5-Oct 31, 1991), 1985-1992 (Box 4, Folder 27-34)